
/* Current Affairs Quiz Questions
 * creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
 */

let questions = [

/* Q1 */     
	{
      numb: 1,
      question: "The employees of which MNC has recently formed a Union in the United States?",
      options: [
                "A) Microsoft",
                "B) Tesla",
                "C) Google",
                "D) Apple"
               ],
      answer: "C) Google"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q2 */     
	{
      numb: 2,
      question: "Who is the head of the panel for conserving Ladakh's land and culture?",
      options: [
                "A) Amit Shah",
                "B) G Kishan Reddy",
                "C) Rao Inderjit Singh",
                "D) Jitendra Singh"
               ],
      answer: "B) G Kishan Reddy"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q3 */     
	{
      numb: 3,
      question: "Kaziranga National Park is located along which Indian River?",
      options: [
                "A) Ganga",
                "B) Yamuna",
                "C) Brahmaputra",
                "D) Sutlej"
               ],
      answer: "C) Brahmaputra"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
	
/* Q4 */     
	{
      numb: 4,
      question: "Which bank acquired the Indian consumer banking businesses of Citibank?",
      options: [
                "A) HDFC Bank",
                "B) Axis Bank",
                "C) ICICI Bank",
                "D) Yes Bank"
               ],
      answer: "B) Axis Bank"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
	
/* Q5 */     
	{
      numb: 5,
      question: "The Lok Sabha passed a bill to merge three municipal corporations of which city into a single entity?",
      options: [
                "A) Mumbai",
                "B) Delhi",
                "C) Kolkata",
                "D) Chennai"
               ],
      answer: "B) Delhi"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q6 */     
	{
      numb: 6,
      question: "Union Environment Ministry has designated which day as 'National Dolphin Day'?",
      options: [
                "A) April 5",
                "B) May 5",
                "C) July 5",
                "D) October 5"
               ],
      answer: "D) October 5"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q7 */     
	{
      numb: 7,
      question: "Which Naval Ship was recently presented the prestigious President's Colour?",
      options: [
                "A) INS Valsura",
                "B) INS Gomati",
                "C) INS Brahmaputra",
                "D) INS Betwa"
               ],
      answer: "A) INS Valsura"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q8 */ 
	{
      numb: 8,
      question: "Which global association released the 'Declaration on Privacy and the protection of personal data'?",
      options: [
                "A) G-20",
                "B) European Union",
                "C) G-7",
                "D) NATO"
               ],
      answer: "B) European Union"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q9 */ 
	{
      numb: 9,
      question: "'Green Triangle' named after Mahatma Gandhi was inaugurated in which country?",
      options: [
                "A) Sri Lanka",
                "B) Nepal",
                "C) Madagascar",
                "D) Myanmar"
               ],
      answer: "C) Madagascar"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q10 */    
	{
      numb: 10,
      question: "'Dishaank' is a land digitisation application of which Indian state?",
      options: [
                "A) Karnataka",
                "B) Kerala",
                "C) Andhra Pradesh",
                "D) Gujarat"
               ],
      answer: "A) Karnataka"
    },
/*Copy till here*/




]; /* Array close*/